DRESTANTO MUHAMMAD DYASPUTRO (DYAS)

dyas@live.com | +6281319883793 | South Jakarta, Indonesia | linkedin.com/in/drestanto



Summary

I am a Software Engineer with **3+ years of experience** that have built IT products for some companies. My skills are more focused on the **back-end and API programming**. I have made a significant impact on work, internships, and projects in the past. I **can create an IT product from scratch or lead a digital product**, proven by my past position, as a CTO and IT Manager.

Work Experience

Nov 2020 - Dec 2022

IT Manager

Equitek (PT Equiti Manajemen Teknologi)

EQUITEK is a management consulting services company and applied technology. Equitek carries out services by implementing Maximizing EBITDA (Operating Profit).

- 1. Improve Client's EBITDA from 600 billion to 1 trillion a year
- 2. Build and Maintain E-learning used by 500+ users
- 3. Lead a Digital Program consisting of 7 experts
- 4. Create a financial dashboard to help C-levels make decisions

Nov 2018 - Feb 2020

Chief Technology Officer (CTO)

Peopleshift (PT Transformasi SDM Indonesia)

Peopleshift is a soft competencies training and consulting provider.

- 1. Acquire 570 LMS users by maintaining a learning platform
- 2. Managing an organized team consisting of 5 people
- 3. Increase client engagement by 20% through an online learning program

May 2017 – Sep 2017

Back-end Developer Intern (during Bachelor)

Meridian.id

Meridian.id is a full-service digital agency, focus on designing and crafting beautiful digital products and experiences.

- 1. Help close one project deal through prototype creation
- 2. Work in a cross-functional team of 5 people

Education

2014 - 2020

Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering

Institut Teknologi Bandung, Indonesia

Thesis: Indonesia Purchasing Power Prediction using Regression Analysis

| Skills & Experience | |
|------------------------------------|--|
| Software Engineering Skills | Back-End Programming (API, WebSocket); Database Development and Management (Relational and Non-relational); Deployment |
| Programming Paradigm | Object oriented; imperative (procedural); functional; declarative; descriptive |
| Software Engineering Experience | JavaScript (including NodeJS and Express); PHP (including Laravel); Python (including Django); Java (native); VBA (Visual Basic for Applications) in Microsoft Office; Linux OS (CentOS, Ubuntu); HTML and CSS basics |
| Database Experience | MySQL; PostgreSQL; MongoDB |
| Projects | |
| Apr 2023 - Oct 2023 | Wiki-like Web App Wiki Wirausaha by KADIN Indonesia 1. Create a wiki-like web for companies and SMEs program matching 2. Maintain web as an IT support |
| Jul 2022 - Sep 2022 | Machine Learning Modeling https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9918765/ 1. Create an ARIMA modeling 2. Create a SEIRD modeling (solving a differential equation) 3. Design a hybrid model using two base models |
| Jul 2017 - Sep 2017 | Attendance and Report System Angklung Web Institute (AWI) 1. Reduce paperwork by almost 100% in the attendance system by automation 2. Introduce data-driven decision-making by attendance dashboard 3. Reduce attendance reporting time by almost 100% through report consolidation |
| Achievements | |
| 2017 | Most Outstanding Student (in Informatics Engineering) ITB Most Outstanding Student 2017 |
| Workshops | |
| August 2019 | Software Architecture Conference by SARCOMM Seminar and Workshop about the journey from monolith to microservices |
| February 2020 | Tokopedia START Summit by Tokopedia Seminar about Tokopedia Academy Launching and Tokopedia inside-out engineering process |
| November 2021 | AllS (Artificial Intelligent Innovation Summit) by KORIKA Seminar about Al Application in Industry |